ICC Lombard, this is the stock which is trading
in double digital today, it is
looking forcibly divided, Varun is explaining the reason for the rise,
Anil ji, the news that has
come today is that ICC Bank is going to increase
its stake in ICC Lombard by 4%
and by September 2024, this
stake will first increase to around 25%,
now it is going to increase by only 4%,
why did the stock rise by 10% for this, you will
remember, in 2019, RBI had issued a circular
where all the banks were asked to
reduce their stake in all their insurance subsidies, after that ICC
Lombard had a deal with Indian Exchange,
under that deal, its stake of around 4% was
reduced and this happened in September 2021
when the bank's stake in ICC Lombard had
reduced to 48% and only then
they had taken approval from IRD that yes,
our stake will be reduced by
8% to 30%, that is  They were going to
reduce their stake of around 18%.
You might remember that recently,
due to the dispute between HDFC Bank and the HDFC manager,
RBI allowed HDFC Bank to keep its stake in Live and Organ beyond 50%.
After this, it was triggered that perhaps ICC
Bank or its relations would also
increase it. In fact, on March 10, RBI had
written a 'You Know' letter to ICC that if you need
more time to reduce your stake, you
can think about it. After that, today
finally ICC Bank said that we will
not reduce it in Lombard but will increase it. So, firstly, there has been a
flood and
secondly, the hangover of
reducing the stake by 18% is over now
and for this you are watching how the
world can make a great pick up in the stock.